Guide to the Harry Scherman Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Harry Scherman Papers,
1937-1969
Scherman, Harry, b. 1887
ca. 19,500 items (49 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079308
Biographical Note
Co-founder and chairman of the board of the Book-of-the-Month Club.
Scope and Content
Large groups of correspondence with members of the editorial board including Henry Seidel Canby, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, John Marquand, Christopher Morley, and William Allen White, which contain insights into the Club's activities, organization, and literary policies. Also, material relating to Scherman's careers as writer, economist, and philanthropist. Mr. Scherman's economic activities are represented by files of correspondence and papers of the National Bureau of Economic Research, the Federal Union, and the Committee on Economic Development. Among the personal items in the collection are manuscripts of his publications, reviews of his writings, numerous awards he has received, photographs, and documents relating to his long and rich career. There are two particularly warm letters from Winston Churchill and Albert Einstein. Also, additional personal and professional correspondence files of Scherman with publishers, agents, authors, Book of the Month Club judges, and organizations with which he was affiliated.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 6 series:
Series I. Cataloged manuscripts
Series II: Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
Series III: Material by and about Harry Scherman
Series IV: Topical Files
Series V: Arranged Correspondence
Series VI: Printed Material
Subjects
Federal Union (U.S.); National Bureau of Economic Research.; Book-of-the-Month Club.; Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961.; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Marquand, John P. (John Phillips), 1893-1960.; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957.; White, William Allen, 1868-1944.; Churchill, Winston, 1874-1965.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955.; Literature publishing.; Publishers and publishing.; Literary agents.; Photoprints.; Committee on Economic Development.; Authors, American.; Philanthropists.; Economists.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 4-49. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1967 M-67 Scherman, Harry Gift
- Series I. Cataloged manuscripts
  - Canby, Henry Siedel. [New York], 8 December 1946. “Broadcast December 8, 1946., (t.ms. 3 p. copy) (Box 1)
  - Canby, Henry Siedel. “Broadcast”[New York], 12 January 1947. January 12, 1947., (t.ms. 2 p. copy) (Box 1)
  - [Canby, Henry Seidl]. n.p., [1948]; [Obituary of] Ross Lockridge. A.ms., (2p, with typewritten copy) (Box 1)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. N.p., [May 1950]; [Review of] “Incredible Tale….” by Gerald W. Johnson., (t. ms., 2p., with corrections in Canby’s hand) (Box 1)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. N.p., [ca. 1950]; [Review of] “Shakespeare in London” by Marchette Chute., (t. ms., 2p, with corrections in Canby’s hand) (Box 1)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. N.p. [1953]; [Review of] “Triumph and Tragedy” by Winston S. Churchill., (t.ms., 4 p, carbon copy) (Box 1)
  - [Canby, Henry Seidel]. Miscellaneous material relating to Canby., (6 items) (Box 1)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. Portrait, in Folder. Inscribed to Henry Scherman by Canby. (Box 1)
  - [Darrow Whitney] [New York], [June 1943];[Biographical sketch of] Christine Weston., (t.ms., 1p.) (Box 1)
  - Fadiman, Clifton. [New York], [June 1958]; [Review of] “Pebble in the pool” by Elizabeth Yates., (t.ms., 1p, with hand written corrections) (Box 1)
  - [Fisher, Dorothy Canfield]. N.p., n.d.; [Introduction to Richard Wright’s Native Soon]., (t.ms., 1p, with appended note in her hand) (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Remarks at Hyde Park, 30 august 1940., (t.ms., carbon with correction in hand by DCF) (Box 1)
  - [Fisher, Dorothy Canfield]. N.p, n.d.; Suggestions from reports for short mention., (t.ms., initialed and with notes in her hand) (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. 1940. Miscellaneous correspondence pertaining to the Children’s Crusade., (9 items) (Box 1)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield., (17 items. Miscellaneous material) (Box 1)
  - Manning, Reg. [New York], 29 January 1947 Cartoon of Harry Scherman. (Box 1)
  - Marquand, John. (February 1947), [Review of “The Frightened Men in the Kremlin” by John Fischer.]., (t.ms., 2p. --pages.7 & 8 only; with corrections in hand by John Marquand) (Box 1)
  - Marquand, John. (Newburyport, Mass. [June 1950]; [Review of Kon-Tiki]., (t.ms., 4p, with corrections in hand by John Marquand) (Box 1)
  - Marquand, John. 6 items. (Box 1)
    (Printed material)
  - Morley, Christopher. [Speech of William Allen White]. [New York], (31 January 1944), (t.ms., 4p, with corrections in hand of Morley) (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry. [New York 1956], [Awards for 1956 of the Louis Lipsky Exchange Fellowship]., (t.ms. 4p.) (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry.n.p. n.d.; “Alice in the Supreme Court.”, (t.ms., 6p, with corrections) (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry. N.p. ca. 1942 “Last Best Hope of Earth”., (t.ms., 1p, with corrections) (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry. n.p.1938 “One-Legged Nation”. T.ms., 18p, with corrections (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry. N.p., [ca.1946]; [Speech on] the Book of the month club, Inc., (t.ms., 17 p, with hand-written corrections) (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry. Philadelphia, 28 March 1960 [Speech before Central High School Philadelphia]., (t.ms., 4p, with handwritten corrections and two related clippings) (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry. N.p., April 1960 [Speech on the book clubs, before the Library of Congress]., (T.ms. 40p.) (Box 1)
  - Scherman, Harry. Washington, 30 April 1945 Testimony before House Banking Committee., (t.ms., 44p., incomplete; with hand-written corrections) (Box 1)
  - White, William Allen. [Emporia] [May 1943];Emporia in Wartime. t.ms., (17p., carbon copy) (Box 1)
- Series II: Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts
  - Adamic, Louis. Milford, N.J., 13 July – 29 Dec 1940 To Harry Scherman, (2 a.l.s., 2 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Adams, J Donald. New York, 29 April 1952 – 28 Nov 1953 To Harry Scherman, (2 a.l.s., 2 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Aydelotte, Frank. To Harry Scherman. Princeton, N.J., Jan-Feb 1948., (1 t.l.s. and 1 t.l.) (Box 2)
  - Baruch, Bernard M.New York, 1 Oct 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 2)
  - Behrman, Samuel Nathaniel. New York, New York, 15 Sept 1960 to Clifton Fadiman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 2)
  - Black, Douglas M. t.l.s. to Harry Scherman, New York, 17 June 1954, (1 p.) (Box 2)
  - Brandt, Carl. t.l.s. to Harry Scherman, New York, 1 Sept 1948, (1 p.) (Box 2)
  - Broun, Heywood. to Harry Scherman. Dallas, San Antonio, January 1939, (2 telegrams) (Box 2)
  - Broun Heywood. Carbon copies to Harry Scherman’s letters to Broun, 1938-1939., (17 items) (Box 2)
  - Brown, John Mason. New York and Stonington, Conn., 12 Feb 1953 – 29 April 1964 to Harry Scherman, (5 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Brunini, John Gilland. New York, 13 Feb 1953 To Harry Scherman, (1 p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Bruno, Harry. [New York] 13 Feb 1953 To John Marquand, (1p. t.l., copy) (Box 2)
  - Buckley, William E. New York 17 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Burns, Arthur New York, June 1952 To Harry Scherman., (2 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Bush, Vannevar. Washington, 22 Sept 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1 p., with carbon copy of letter from Bush to Winston Churchill) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. [New York], 25 Feb 1946 t.l. to Book-of-the-Month-Club judges, 2p. (carbon copy (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. V.p., 1943-1956 To Harry Scherman., (21 a.l.s., 14 t.l.s., 3 t.l., 2 p.c.s., 2 telegrams, 1 cablegram) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. New York, 22 Dec 1951. To Ralph Thompson, (2p. a.l.s., carbon copy of Thompson’s reply is included) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. New York [Grenada] 1953-1954, (1 t.l. and 1 telegram to Meredith Woods.) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. 1941-1945 Carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to Canby (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. 1946-1956 Carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to Canby. (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. 1941-1956 Carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to Canby., (73 items) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. New York, 12 July 1945. To Amy Loveman., (a.l.s. 2p.) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. Clinton, Conn., 23 September 1947. to Harry Scherman., (a.l.s. 1p.) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel. West Cornwall and Clinton, Conn., 31 July 1949 – 29 Aug 1950 to Meredith Wood, (3 a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Canby, Marion Gause (Mrs. Henry Siedeln.p. 1956 & 1958 To Harry Scherman. Deep River, Conn., (2 a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Canfield, Cass. New York, 21 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Cerf, Bennett A. New York, 17 June 1954 t.l.s. to Harry Scherman. 1p. (Box 2)
  - Churchill, Winston S. Westerham, 2 May 1955 To Harry Scherman, (1 p. t.l.s., with envelope) (Box 2)
  - Churchill, Winston. Westerham, Kent, 18 October 1949. to Harry Scherman, telegram (Box 2)
  - Connolly, Jeannette. New York, 23 July 1947 – 12 March 1948 to Dorothy Canfield Fisher, (3 t.l.s. Mrs. Fisher’s replies to these three letters are appended) (Box 2)
  - Cousins, Norman. New York, 10 Feb 1966 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Crowell, Robert L. t.l.s. to New York, 17 June 1954 Harry Scheman, 1p. (Box 2)
  - Darrow, Whitney. New York, 21 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Davenport, Basil. District Intelligence Office, APO 516, 30 May 1944t.l.s. to Harry Scherman, 7 p. (Box 2)
  - Dello Joio, Norman. [New York] 25 Jan 1967 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 2)
  - De Severesky, Alexander Procofieff (for list of items see Seversky) (Box 2)
  - Douglas, William Orville. Beverly Hills, Caliand Washington, 30 June [1962] (Box 2)
  - Einstein, Albert1p. Princeton, 2 May 1944. a.l.s. to Harry Scherman (Box 2)
  - Erskine, John. New York, 30 Dec 1926 – 7 Jan 1927 to Robert K. Haas, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Fadiman, Clifton. New York [June 1950]; to Amy Loveman, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 2)
  - Fadiman, Clifton. New York, 1 March 1949 To “Members of the Board, (t.l.s., 3 p.) (Box 2)
  - Fadiman, Clifton. v.p. 16 May 1944 – 7 Nov 1967. to Harry Scherman, (20 a.l.s., 4 a.p.c.s., 45 t.l.s., 3 t.l., 8 telegrams) (Box 2)
  - Fadiman, Clifton. New York, 19 June 1944 to George Wolfson, (t.l., 1p.) (Box 2)
  - Fadiman, Clifton. New York, 5 Nov 1946 – 21 Oct [1950]. To Meredith Wood, (4 a.l.s., 1 t.l.s., 1 telegram) (Box 2)
  - Farrar, John. New York, 21 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. May 1938December 1941.; Carbon copies of letters of Harry Scherman to D.C.F., (91 items) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. October 1939 – September1941. Carbon copies of letters of Harry Scherman to D.C.concerning the Children’s Crusade, (59 items) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. April 1940 carbon copies of letters of Dorothy Canfield Fisher related to the Children’s Crusade, (9 items) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. vt., 24 Sept 1940 telegram to Henry Abrams. Arlington (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. N.p., June 1940 & [Sept 1941]; To members of the Jury of Awards of the Children’s Crusade., (1 telegram and 1 t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - [Fisher, Dorothy Canfield]. N.p., [March 1940] To Herbert Hoover, (2p. t.l., draft) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. n.p., 24 Sept 1941 To Dr. Andree Royon, (1p. t.l. carbon) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. V.p., 1937 – 1958 & n.d.; To Harry Scherman., (82 t.l.s, 20 a.l.s., 7 t.l., 4 a.n.s., 3 a.n., 1 t.n.s., 16 telegrams) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. V.t, 10 Nov 1939 To Mr. and Mrs. Harry Scherman., (2p. t.l.s) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. New York, 3 April 1940 To “Sponsor”, (1 p. printed letter) (Box 3)
  - [Fisher, Dorothy Canfield]. Arlington, Vt. 11 October 1939 [to the State Commissions of Education, (2p. t.l. draft) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. N.p., [July 1940]; To unknown correspondent, (5p. t.l. draft; with note to Harry Scherman, initialed D.C.F.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. N.P., [Dec 1940]; To unknown correspondent (p.s. to a letter, forwarded to Harry Scherman by Marion Canby, (t.l.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. 1938-1958 carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to D.C. Fisher,., (402 items.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. 1942 – 1943 Carbon copies of letters of Harry Scherman to D.C.F.., (52 items) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Carbon copies of letters of Harry Scherman to D.C.F., (65 items) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. 1947-1948 carbon copies of letters of Harry Scherman to D.C.F.., (43 items.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Arlington, Vt. 26 March 1946 – 16 Feb 1948 to Jeanette Connolly, (1 a.l.s., 3 a.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. 1949–1951. Carbon copies of letters of Harry Scherman to D.C.F.., (41 items.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Arlington, Vt., 22 Sept [1950]; to miss Geier, (a.l.s., 2 p.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. 1952-1958Carbon copies of letters of Harry Scherman to D.C.F.., (42 items.) (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Arlington, Vt. [Jan 1949]; to Miss Gutersloh, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Arlington, Vt., 7 Feb – 21 Sept 1949 to Joan Hoffman, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Arlington, Vt., 10 May [1939] – 25 July 1949 to Harry Scherman, (6 t.l.s., 1 t.p.c.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Arlington, Vt., 4 February 1949 To Sidney Butler Smith; telegram (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Albany, 22 December 1947. To Mollie Stoller, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. Arlington, Vt., 24 July 1949 – 2 Oct 1950 to Meredith Wood, (2 a.l.s., 12 t.l.s., 2 telegrams.) (Box 4)
  - Fisher, John R. To Harry Scherman. Arlington, Vt., 1942-1956, (4 t.l.s. and 2 telegrams) (Box 4)
  - Ford, Dorothy B. (Mrs. John W.) To John Marquand, Youngstown, Ohio, 1 March 1948, (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Griede, Donald. To Harry Scherman, New York, 17 June 1954., (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Giroux, Robert. To Harry Scherman, New York, 18 June 1954., (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Haas, Robert K. To Harry Scherman. New York, 1947-1954., (3 t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Haydn, Hiram New York, 24 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s. ,signed by a secretary) (Box 4)
  - Highet, Gilbert. East Hampton, N.Y., 30 August 1957 – 5 June 1958. to miss Housden, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Highet, Gilbert. v.p., 28 March 1954 – 7 Feb 1968 to Harry Scherman, (2 a.l.s., 20 t.l.s., 2 telegrams) (Box 4)
  - Hobson, Thayer. New York, 17 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Horgan, Paul. Middletown, Conn., 21 May 1969 to Harry Scherman, (2 a.l.s., 12 t.l.s., 2 telegrams.) (Box 4)
  - Huddleston, Martha. New York, 19 Jan 1951;.To Dorothy Canfield Fisher, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Jackson, Barbara Ward (Lady), 11May – 2 June 1964 St. Brelade and London, (1 a.l.s., 1 t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Kent, Rockweell. Ausable Forks, N.Y., 15 March 1943 To Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 4)
  - Kerr, Charles. New Haven, 22 June 1945.To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s., signed by his secretary) (Box 4)
  - Klopfer, Donald S. New York, 18 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Knopf, Alfred A. New York, 19 Jan 1948.To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s., carbon copy of related letter from Scherman enclosed) (Box 4)
  - Lilienthel, David E. Washington, 15 Oct 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 4)
  - Lippman, Walter. Washington, 15 May 1964 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 4)
  - Lockridge, Ross Franklin, Jr. N.p., 30 Oct 1947 To Henry Seidel Canby, (4p. t.l.s) (Box 4)
  - Lottinville, Savoie. Norman, Okla., 8 Jun 1954 t.l.s. to Henry Seidel Canby, 1p. t.l.s. (Box 4)
  - Loveman, Amy. New York, 14 Nov 1951 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 4)
  - Lynes, Russell. New York, 14 Oct 1946 To John Marquand, (1p. t.l.s., with 2p.t.l.s. note signed by John Fischer) (Box 4)
  - MacInness, Helen. New York, 1 March 1966 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s., 2p) (Box 4)
  - Mann, Thomas. Pacific Palisades, Calif., 29 Oct 1951 to “Book-of-the-Month-Club”, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 4)
  - Mann, Thomas. Pacific Palisades, Calif., 5 Jan 1952 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1 p) (Box 4)
  - McCormick, Ken. 22 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, New York., (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - McDonald, James G. Brooklyn, N.Y., 26 June 1940 To Dorothy Canfield Fischer, (1p. t.l.s., with an initialed note by D. C. F.) (Box 4)
  - Macrae, Elliott. New York, 13 Nov 1968 To Dorothy Canfield Fisher,. New York, 10 June 1958., (1p. t.l.s.) (Box 4)
  - Mannes, Marya. New York, 13 Nov 1968 to Harry Scherman., (t.l.s.1p.) (Box 4)
  - Marquand, John. 1944-1946 carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to Marquand., (34 items) (Box 5)
  - Marquand, John. 1944-1948 carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to Marquand., (44 items) (Box 5)
  - Marquand, John. 1949-1958 carbon copies of Harry Scherman’s letters to Marquand., (37 items) (Box 5)
  - Martin, Ellis R. Chelsea, Mich., 27 March 1958 to Dorothy Canfield Fisher, (t.l. 1p, with covering letter from D.C.F.’s secretary) (Box 5)
  - Melcher, Frederic G. New York, 21 June 1954 To Harry Scherman, (1p. t.l.s., signed by his secretary) (Box 5)
  - Minton, Melville. London, 18 June 1954 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr. Washington D.C. 16 Sept 1943. to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Baltimore, 6 July 1938. To Harry Scherman, (telegram 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 6 October 1938 To Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 30 July n.y. to Harry Scherman., (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. 1938-1941 Carbon copies of Harry Scherman letters to Morley, (29 items) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 20 March 1939 to Harry Scherman., (a.l.s. 1p) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 28 April 1939 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, 5 July 1939 to Harry Scherman., (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Crater Club, Essex County, N.Y., 6 September 1939., (a.l.s. 2p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 11 January 1940 to Harry Scherman., (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., March 1940 ? To Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 1p. with enclosure) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 7 Feb 1941 to Meredith Wood, (t.l.s. 1p. with related letter) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 14 November 1941 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p, with enclosure) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 9 November 1942 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p, with related letter) (Box 5)
    (for letter from Robert Moses referred to in the above, see: Moses, Robert. N.Y., 7 November 1942 to Christopher Morley; t.l.s. 1p.)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 26 December 1942. To Harry Scherman, (a.l.s., 1p, with related letters) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., [ca. 30 January 1943] to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s., 1p, with related letters) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 4 February 1943 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p with related letter) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 19 February 1943 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 1p, with related letter) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 5 March 1943 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 2p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 17 April 1943 to Harry Scherman., (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 25 July 1943 to Meredith Wood, (t.l.s. 1p, with related material) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 1 Aug 1943 to Harry Scherman., (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 15 September 1943 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p, with related letter) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 18 October 1943 to Meredith Wood, (t.l.s. 1p, with related material) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 2 Jan 1944 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 14 July 1944 to Meredith Wood, (a.l.s. 1p with related material) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 17 Aug 1944 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p, with related letter) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 9 Sept 1944 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 11 December 1944 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 9 January 1945 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 29 January [1945] to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 5 March (1945to Harry Scherman, (a.p.c.s.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 6 June 1945 to Harry Scherman, (a.p.c.s.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 18 July 1945 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p, with related letter) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. N.Y., 28 August 1945 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, N.Y., 22 February 1946 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 5)
  - Morley, Christopher. Calgary, Alta, Canada, 15 July 1946 to Meredith Wood., (a.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Vancouver, 4 Aug 1946 to Harry Scherman, (a.l.s. 2p, with related clipping) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. New York, 25 Sept 1946 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p proxy signature by secretary) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. New York, 27 September 1946 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. New York, 4 Nov 1946 to Meredith Wood, (a.l.s. 1p, with related letter) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 31 December 1946 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 14 August 1947 to Meredith Wood, (t.l.s. 1p, with a.n.s. by recipient) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Aboard the S S Empress of Canada, 3 October 1947 to Harry Scherman, (a.p.c.s.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 11 February 1948 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 23 June 1948 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s.; 1p, with enclosure) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 9 Dec 1948 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p, with related material) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 18 Jan 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 15 February 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 20 April 1949 to Harry Scherman, (p.c.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 29 April 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 1 July 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 2p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 14 July 1949 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p, with related material) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 8 Aug 1950 to Amy Loveman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 17 April 1951 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 2p) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 11 May 1951 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p, with related material) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 30 May 1951 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 19 June 1951, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 26 October 1951 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s. 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 13 November 1951 to Harry Scherman, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 6)
  - Morley, Christopher. Roslyn Heights, New York, 30 Dec 1951 to Harry Scherman, (p.c.s.) (Box 6)